<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<usfx xmlns:ns0="http://eBible.org/usfx.xsd" ns0:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="usfx.xsd">
  <languageCode>eng</languageCode>
  <book id="3JN">
    <id id="3JN">Vibe Bible Translation - 3 John</id>
    <h>3 John</h>
    <toc level="1">The Third Letter of John</toc>
    <toc level="2">3 John</toc>
    <toc level="3">3Jn</toc>
    <p sfm="mt">The Third Letter of John</p>
    <c id="1" />
    <p>
      <v id="1" />The elder to Gaius the beloved, whom I love in truth.<f caller="+">Greek: ὁ πρεσβύτερος (ho presbyteros) - 'the elder', likely referring to the apostle John</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="2" />Beloved, I pray that in all things you may prosper and be in good health, just as your soul prospers.<f caller="+">Greek: εὐοδοῦσθαι (euodousthai) - 'to prosper, have a good journey'; ψυχή (psyche) - 'soul', referring to spiritual well-being</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="3" />For I rejoiced greatly when brothers came and testified of your truth, how you walk in truth.<ve />
      <v id="4" />I have no greater joy than these things, that I hear my children are walking in the truth.<f caller="+">Greek: ἀλήθεια (aletheia) - 'truth', a key Johannine theme appearing 6 times in this short letter</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="5" />Beloved, you do faithfully whatever you work for the brothers and for strangers,<ve />
      <v id="6" />who testified of your love before the church, whom you will do well to send forward on their journey in a manner worthy of god,<f caller="+">Note: 'god' not capitalized following original manuscript convention</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="7" />for they went out for the sake of the name, taking nothing from the gentiles.<f caller="+">Greek: τοῦ ὀνόματος (tou onomatos) - 'the name', referring to the name of Jesus Christ</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="8" />We therefore ought to receive such men, that we may become fellow workers for the truth.<ve />
      <v id="9" />I wrote something to the church, but Diotrephes, who loves to be first among them, does not receive us.<f caller="+">Greek: φιλοπρωτεύων (philoproteuon) - 'loving to be first', describing pride and ambition for preeminence</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="10" />Therefore, if I come, I will remember his works which he does, speaking evil words against us with malicious talk. And not being satisfied with these things, he himself does not receive the brothers, and those who want to he forbids and casts out from the church.<ve />
      <v id="11" />Beloved, do not imitate the evil but the good. The one doing good is from god; the one doing evil has not seen god.<ve />
      <v id="12" />Demetrius has been testified to by all and by the truth itself; and we also testify, and you know that our testimony is true.<ve />
      <v id="13" />I had many things to write to you, but I do not want to write to you with ink and pen;<ve />
      <v id="14" />but I hope to see you soon, and we will speak face to face.<f caller="+">Greek: στόμα πρὸς στόμα (stoma pros stoma) - literally 'mouth to mouth', an idiom meaning face to face conversation</f>
      <ve />
      <v id="15" />Peace to you. The friends greet you. Greet the friends by name.<f caller="+">Greek: κατ' ὄνομα (kat' onoma) - 'by name', indicating personal, individual greetings</f>
      <ve />
    </p>
  </book>
</usfx>
